Baltimore, MD USA github.com/g-s-k

 $\begin{array}{c} {\rm kaplan.george@outlook.com} \\ {\rm +1.518.852.4731} \end{array}$ 

## Summary

Programming Languages: JavaScript / TypeScript, Rust, Elixir, Golang, MATLAB, SCSS, LATEX

Frameworks & Tools: React, Phoenix, Serverless / AWS Lambda, Docker, Kubernetes, Cargo, Make

Interests: Music and audio technology, generative art, user experience and accessibility, compilers

# Experience

#### **Fearless Solutions**

Software Engineer 2

March 2021 — present

- ▶ Adopted and expanded a prototype application built with *React* and the *Serverless Framework* into a production-ready state, and delivered it to users on time. The improvements included support for data migration scripts, multiple new user types and workflows, and integration with legacy systems via *Kafka*.
- > Spearheaded an effort among technical personnel to improve code quality, test coverage, and user accessibility. This led to a significant decrease in defects and regressions pushed into our staging environment.
- ▷ Collaborated with security and operations teams to address findings from a pre-deployment audit. All findings were eliminated well in advance of the subsequent audit, and the deployment to production was able to proceed without incident.

#### Visionist Incorporated

Engineer 3

November 2020 — February 2021

- ▶ Maintained and enhanced a group of analytics for audio data using Elixir as the API layer and Rust to implement the signal processing algorithms. These were integrated using the *Rustler* library, and were chosen for Rust's performance characteristics and Elixir's robust operation in high-throughput systems.
- ▶ Fleshed out a system management interface from a minimal scaffold into a useful tool for systems administrators using the *Phoenix LiveView* library.

 $Engineer\ 2$ 

August 2018 — October 2020

- ▶ Helped scale a suite of applications for real-time geographic data analysis up from prototype to production, focusing on performance and reliability. Improved communication between the development team and our user base to implement a faster and more robust feedback loop.
- ▶ Built and maintained a richly interactive web form using *React* to give users fine-grained control over their analytic rules. Incorporated usability recommendations from our UX specialists, feature requests from our users, and technical requirements from our contract in each iteration of the design.

### Nu-Tek Precision Optical Corporation

Engineer 1

May 2016 — August 2018

- Developed and maintained a proprietary MATLAB toolbox for processing a variety of optical data formats, supporting common manipulations such as Zernike decomposition, FFT analysis, and automated generation of corrective programs for computer-controlled polishing machines.
- $\triangleright$  Automated various administrative tasks such as printing work orders, tracking progress on each project, and generating customer documentation with *PowerShell* and  $\LaTeX$ .

.....

### Education

# University of Maryland, College Park

Bachelor's of Science in Physical Sciences

2012 - 2016

> Concentrations in Atmospheric and Oceanic Science, Chemistry, and Geology